<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | L</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfume search engine</title>
      <link>/project/perfume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/perfume/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of searching perfumes and purchasing perfume are &lt;strong&gt;seperated&lt;/strong&gt; from each other. The perfume shopping website does not provide much detailed product information, such as the front, middle, and back notes, perfumers, etc. Similarly, perfume review site do not provide functionalities like navigation to the shopping page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a user who want to buy perfumes but are not familiar with them, I have to go to perfume review websites like Nosetime or Xiaohongshu to look for a perfume that I like. However, if I have decided what to buy, I have to search again on shopping website like Taobao.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no specific perfume shopping website on the market, which brings a lot of trouble to users&amp;rsquo; demands.
Therefore, this perfume searching and shopping site is designed and developed to meet the personalized purchase needs of users by integrated and all-round information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User could search perfumes by text and image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User could be navigated to the shopping site in the result page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User could combine different features to dig out favourite product.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The text searching function is implemented through Apache Lucene. The image recognition is implemented using ORB operator and brute force matcher provided by OpenCV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;interface&#34;&gt;Interface&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Menu Page:
&lt;img src=&#34;3.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
Search by Text:
&lt;img src=&#34;2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
Search by Image:
&lt;img src=&#34;1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
Muti-field Search:
&lt;img src=&#34;4.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;6.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
Search Result:
&lt;img src=&#34;5.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;7.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-features&#34;&gt;More Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leverage regular crawlers of Taobao and Nosetime to collect information on a daily basis to keep the database information up-to-date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fuzzy Search to improve the robustness of the seaching function.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offer suggestions based on search and web history before user finish typing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Price prediction, personalized product recommendation based on the data collected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Monitoring</title>
      <link>/project/sentiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/sentiment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On GitHub, issue reports are used by team members to ask for advice, and express and share opinions related to software maintenance and evolution.
Issue data can be mined to explore developers emotions, sentiments and politeness&amp;mdash;affects for short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is becoming apparent that emotion awareness, awareness of one&#39;s own emotions and those of others, is crucial for a software company and for many stakeholders involved in the software development lifecycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to improve Emotion or Sentiment awareness in Open Source Software developments. Although monitoring systmes for emotion phenomena detection has been studied in social media, there is no studies on tools to monitor sentiment phenomena in software development communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This design could provide an alternative view to evaluate the health status of open source software projects (from a social and pshychological point of view).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;workflow&#34;&gt;Workflow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;system.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All the data is automatically collected using &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.github.com/v3/&#34;&gt;REST API v3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sentiment Analysis is performed using SentiCR and an SE-specific sentiment lexicon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Burst detection is implemented through Kleinburg model and Event extraction is fulfilled through LDA Topic extraction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-analysis-and-visualization&#34;&gt;Data Analysis and Visualization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visualization of sentiment status of all the &lt;strong&gt;commit&lt;/strong&gt; comments in a given repository (individual work):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;vscode.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visualization of all the &lt;strong&gt;issue&lt;/strong&gt; comments in a given repository (collaborative work):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;sentiment-analysis.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two graphs can provide a general idea of the sentiment status of the project by simply displaying the generated time series and summary information. Based on them, I further design some interfaces for the sentiment monitoring system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;examples&#34;&gt;Examples&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Project Manager, I want to know whether there is a burst of a certain sentiment and what events lead to such sentiment phenomena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prototype of Burst Detection and Event Extraction:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detected events could link to corresponding GitHub pages, enabling user to know details of the event.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User could select a specific time period and the system will detect sentiment burst and related events during this period. Typical comments will also be listed with sentiment score and keywords displayed to the user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For better accuracy, user could adjust number of events to be detected by the model during the burst period.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User could watch the project he/she is interested in. Whenever there is new detection, user could receive notifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;sentiment.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Software Quality Assurance team member, I want to see the overall sentiment state of the project in the past period such as one week, one month, one year, etc., so that I can correlate it with other metrics, such as productivity, task quality, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prototype of information visualization and summary on a given time period:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enabling sliding window for adaptive visualization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide selection on time period and look for database or automatically collect data during that period from GitHub.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide issue and commit comment data summary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatically compare the result with the summary over the last period.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give advice based on some embeded knowledge. (e.g, Since research has found that positive sentiment can reduce issue resolution time, the system can help QA team member to evaluate productivity accordingly.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;visualize.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vocal Elimination</title>
      <link>/project/voice-elimination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/voice-elimination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introdcution&#34;&gt;Introdcution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove the voices of human from a stereo song and get pure music (the sound of the instrument).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audio format: mp3/wav&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tool: MATLAB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keywords: sampling, FFT, filter, channel mixer, inversion and etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vocal elimination is a technique that eliminates the vocals of stereo songs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vocal elimination is a simple DSP application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;principles&#34;&gt;Principles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Features of Stereo music: In stereo music, the instrument sound in the left and right channels is different in stereo music, especially the various instruments in the song are placed in the left and right channels; while the human voice is generally the same in both channels.
In this course design, we mainly apply this property to achieve the effect of vocal elimination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Features of vocal: The sound image position of human voice is in the center of the entire sound field (balanced distribution of left and right channels); the sound frequency is concentrated in the middle and high frequency parts.
We know that the instrument sound in the left and right channels is different in stereo music, especially the various instruments in the song are placed in the left and right channels, but the vocals in the two channels is exactly the same. Then, you can use this property to eliminate vocals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oracle Bone Character Recognition</title>
      <link>/project/oracle-bone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/oracle-bone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oracle bone inscriptions (OBIs) are some of the oldest characters of Chinese words, which were hieroglyphic signs inscribed onto cattle bones or turtle shells with sharp objects about 3000 years ago. OBIs are very important to exploit the political systems, economic status and social lives of Shang Dynasty (about 1600 B.C. -1046 B.C.), the ﬁrst dynasty recorded by Chinese words found so far. However, few people have the literacy of OBIs. The recognition of OBIs, which interdisciplinarily combines archaeology, history, philology and literature, requires people to have plenty of knowledge and years of experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;data-set&#34;&gt;Data set&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;models&#34;&gt;Models&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CNN: We adapt AlexNet, altering its kernel sizes, paddings, numbers of channels, and strides, for this task.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SIFT/SURF: We adopt two methods for scale and rotation invariant interest point/feature detector and descriptor: Scale Invariant Feature Transform (SIFT) and Speed Up Robust Features (SURF). After extracting features, we perform a quick and efﬁcient matching by using the FLANN (Fast Approximate Nearest Neighbor Search Library).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Template matching is a technique for ﬁnding areas of an image that match (are similar) to a template image (patch). Template matching works by &amp;ldquo;sliding&amp;rdquo; the template across the original image. As it slides, it compares or matches the template to the portion of the image directly under it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;experiment-results&#34;&gt;Experiment Results:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;real-scence-tests&#34;&gt;Real Scence Tests:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
